Guide to Belva Ann Lockwood Papers: The Ormes-Winner Collection, ca. 1879-1904.
Fenimore Art Museum
Belva Ann Lockwood Papers: The Ormes-Winner Collection, ca. 1879-1904.
.5 cu. ft.
Winner, Julia Hull, 1904-1980
Fenimore Art Museum Research Library 80 Lake Road Cooperstown, NY 13326 Research Library
Coll. No. 213
Gift; Julia Hull Winner, Gasport, NY; 1971; FM-60.71
Lockwood's grandson, DeForest L. Ormes of Washington, D.C., presented this collection to Mrs. Julia Hull Winner of Gasport, N.Y., Town of Royalton Historian, who was writing a biography of Lockwood. The biography was published by the Niagara County Historical Association in 1969. In 1971, Mrs. Winner donated the collection to the New York State Historical Association.
Library has microfilm copies of this collection (Microfilm 12-4).
Coll. No. 213: Belva Ann Lockwood Papers: The Ormes-Winner Collection is open for research according to the regulations of Fenimore Art Museum Library.
Belva Ann Lockwood (1830-1917), a noted lawyer and a National Equal Rights presidential candidate, was a native of the Town of Royalton, Niagara County, New York. She ran for president of the United States in the election of 1884, becoming the first woman to run a full-scale presidential campaign.
Lockwood, Belva Ann, 1830-1917; lawyers; Women.; Women's rights.; United States. Supreme Court.; manuscripts (documents); clippings (information artifacts); diplomas; passports
This collection contains about 500 manuscript pages of Lockwood's various lectures, including some from the time of her campaign for president; newspaper clippings about her; an 1879 diploma presented to Lockwood when she was allowed to practice law before the United States Supreme Court; and an 1889 passport.
- 213.1/1 -- Biographical material: newspaper clippings and a photograph of a display about Lockwood., 1937 - ca. 1968.
- 213.1/2 -- Belva Lockwood's passport., 1889
- 213.1/3 -- "The New Woman," 75 pages, numbered 1-127, with omissions., u.d.
- 213.1/4 -- "Women in Professions," pages 1-24, 42-51, 34-79, and twenty-two others., u.d.
- 213.1/5 -- "Women in Professions," sixty-five pages numbered 48-125; incomplete., u.d.
- 213.1/6 -- "On Marriage.", u.d.
- 213.1/7 -- "On Marriage.", 1904, undated.
- 213.1/8 -- "Prosperity and Existing Conditions," pages 3-6 and 8-14; typescript., u.d.
- 213.1/9 -- "Equal Rights," pages 19-38, 40-41, and 49-52; typescript., u.d.
- 213.1/10 -- "Across the Continent and What I Saw," pages 31-44, 52-68, and 70-72, with typescript; "Suffrage," pages 141-145; Memorial Day speech, pages 1-8 and 1314., u.d.
- 213.1/11 -- "Temperance," about 75 pages, u.d.
- 213.1/12 -- Portions of various lectures., u.d.
- 213.1/13 -- Portions of various lectures., ca. 1895.
- 213.1/14 -- Portions of various lectures, an indenture, and newspaper clippings., 1882-1892, undated.
- 213.1/15 -- Portions of various lectures, u.d.
- 213.1/16 -- Photograph: composite of portraits of women's rights advocates - A.W.M. Bartlett, Madame Aneka, Laura C. Dundore, Kattie I. French, Lucretia Mott, D.B. Briggs, Laura Gordon, Mary E. Walker, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Phoebe Couzins, Belva A. Lockwood, C.S. Lozier, Pauline W. Davis, Martha C. Wright, Matilda Joslin Gage, and Charlotte B. Wilbour., u.d.
- 213.01 -- Certificate to practice law before the U.S. Supreme Court issued to Belva Lockwood, 1879